Preliminary Inventory to the Julius Klein Papers, 1928-1952
Hoover Institution Archives
Julius Klein Papers,
1928-1952
56015
Klein, Julius, 1886-
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Transcripts of radio broadcasts, transcripts of speeches, and correspondence, relating to American economic conditions, foreign trade, and economic policy during the administration of President Herbert Hoover.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; United States. Dept. of Commerce.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.
Biographical Note
1921-1929 Director, Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce
1929-1933 Under Secretary of Commerce
Container List
- 1928
  - A Week of the World's Business - What Foreign Trade Means to the Average American (Box 1)
  - Some Problems of our Domestic Business
  - Our International Balance Sheet
  - American Investments Abroad
  - American Investments Abroad (second talk on this subject)
  - Trade Barriers -- What is being done to minimize them?
  - Trade Barriers -- What is being done to minimize them? (second Talk)
  - The American Struggle Against Foreign Raw-Material Controls
  - America Motorizing Mankind
  - Foreign Triumphs of the American Automobile
  - China in Transition: Conflict and Commerce
  - Picturesque Phases of our Trade with China
  - Our Neighbor to the North, and Her Markets for our Goods
  - The New Germany: Her Commercial and Industrial Recovery
  - The Independent Retailer: His Position and Prospects
  - Foreign Quinine Monopoly Relinquishes Its Grip
  - Factors Favoring the Independent Merchant Today
  - Practical Aids for the Independent Merchant
  - Does Factory Efficiency Increase Unemployment?
  - "Servicing" Jobs Available for Displaced Factory Workers
  - Adventures on the Far Frontiers of Trade
  - The Romance of Rubber
  - Trade Rivalries Abroad
  - International Cartels and What They Mean to Us
  - Cooperation in World Trade
  - The New Pan-Americanism
  - Swinging Down the West Coast
  - Chile and Peru: From the Equator to Cape Horn
  - The River Plate Countries
  - Brazil: A South American Colossus
  - The Progress of the United States in the Past Half-Century
- 1929
  - Uncle Sam Strides Forward: A Record of Five Decades
  - The Cancer of Economic Waste
  - Wielding the Scalpel on Waste
  - Helping the Grocer Solve His Problems
  - Utilize Wood -- and Save the Forests
  - Radical Reforms in the Utilization of Wood
  - Defective Distribution: Our Greatest Business Problem
  - Commercial Europe To-Day
  - Commercial Europe of Today (2nd talk)
  - Awakening Morocco
  - Seven Years of Business Progress
  - Speeding Up Our Economic Progress
  - Measuring and Mapping Our Country and Its Costs
  - Modern Greece and Its Markets
  - Czechoslovakia: Its Industry and Trade
  - Protecting American Lives and Property on the Water
  - The Romance of World Radio
  - The Cash-Book of the Nation's Foreign Business
  - Adjusting our Trade Balances
  - Present-Day Austria and Its Commercial Problems
  - Commercial Hungary and Its Relations with America
  - Exporting Highways: What Foreign Road-Building Means for our Trade
  - Our Aircraft Abroad
  - The World's Business on Wings
  - Rayon and Its Place in Industry Today
  - Must We "Adapt" American Manufactures for Foreign Markets?
  - The Economic Position of Great Britain To-Day
  - New Ideas in International Advertising
  - Advertising American Goods Abroad
  - Advertising Abroad
  - The Business Outlook
  - Keeping the Retailer Off "The Rocks"
  - Business and World Peace
  - Checking up on Retail Credits
  - Prosperity Insurance Through Coordinated Effort
  - Government Aid in Business Betterment
  - Credits and Retail Failures
  - Effective Retail Salesmanship
  - Helping the Wholesaler Cut Costs
  - Marshaling Facts
- 1930
  - American Business at the Turn of the Year (Box 2)
  - Our American Advance Since 1880
  - Commercial Triumphs of the Nineteen-Twenties
  - The Machine, the Test-Tube -- and Business
  - Regional Cooperation in Business
  - The Menace of Obsolescence
  - The Battle to Preserve Materials
  - George Washington as a Business Man
  - Beauty as a Business-Builder
  - Art in Industry Pays Dividends
  - Commercial Forces in Contemporary Spain
  - American Influence and Interest in Spain
  - Present-Day Portugal and Its Trade
  - Construction as a Factor in Prosperity
  - The Business of Sports
  - American Profits from Foreign Pastimes
  - The New Far East
  - Squandering Business Experience
  - Minimizing Mine Perils
  - Business Aspects of Vacation
  - Roads as Business-Builders
  - The Zeppelin and German Aviation
  - Traffic Safety as a Business Asset
  - Mastering the Traffic Menace
  - The Flexible Tariff Clause
  - Explosives as a Civilizing Force
  - The Potency of "Invisible" Payments
  - The New Business of Refrigeration
  - Assembling Your Vacation Requisites
  - The United States as a Debtor Nation
  - A New Day for the Patent Office
  - Serving the Cause of Safety at Sea
  - How Science Serves the Mariner
  - What Heights and Measures Mean to the Housewife
  - What are the People Doing for a Living?
  - Flying the Department of Commerce Airways
  - The Electrical Servant
  - The European Business Depression
  - Public Construction as an Aid to Business
  - The Drive for Better Homes
  - Latin-American Trade Outlook
  - Simplification and Its Meaning
  - Control of the Business Cycle
  - Factors Affecting Foreign Trade
  - Controlling our National Surveys
  - The American Seamen
  - The Romance of Radio Regulation
  - Keeping Abreast of Business
  - Alaska: Its Fur Seals and Fisheries
  - Men and Mines
  - Retailing as a Science
  - European Business Outlook
- 1931
  - Business at the Turn of the Year
  - The Building and Loan Centennial
  - New Commercial Picture of the Pacific Southwest
  - The Challenge of the Machine
  - Business Cooperation
  - Model Stores Mean Retail Profits
  - Why Some Retailers Fail
  - The Retail Morgue
  - The Work of the United States Department of Commerce
  - Constructing Prosperity
  - Are We Losing Out in Foreign Trade?
  - Siam and Its Commerce
  - A New Move Toward Better Business
  - A Few Facts about Furniture
  - That Installment Bogey
  - Saving by Simplicity
  - Water Power and Steam
  - Yugoslavia: A Country of the Future
  - Is Uncle Sam a Skinflint?
  - The Business Future of the Small Town
  - Factors Favoring Small-Town Business
  - Helpful Bureaucracy
  - America's Enormous Invisible Payments
  - Vacation Business
  - Surveying Business
  - America's Stake in European Stability
  - The Business of Radio
  - What We Buy from Abroad
  - Where the Money Goes
  - Commercial Cooperation with Latin America
  - America's Sweet Tooth
  - The French Empire and Its Trade
  - The New Turkey and Its Markets
  - The Railways and Business
  - Beating the Slump
  - Negro Education and Economic Development
  - The Business of Providing Jobs
  - Beating the Slump No. II
  - Gold and Trade
  - Our Merchant Marine
  - China and Its Trade Today
  - The Bugbear of Bureaucracy
  - Christmas and the Retailer
- 1932
  - Government Business Publications (Box 3)
  - A Great New Business Building
  - Some Problems of the Retailer
  - One Way to Lower Prices
  - Science Serving the Consumers
  - Consumers' New Importance
  - The Greeting-Card Business
  - Washington, Practical Man of Affairs
  - The Laundry Business: A Significant Service Industry
  - Developments Affecting Trans-Pacific Trade
  - Small Business Has Its Inning
  - The Drug Store in the Spot Light
  - Labor Conditions in Europe
  - One Another's Burdens
  - Bargains in Brains
  - European Budgets
  - A Lesson from the Dinosaur
  - Telling the World
  - Export Business Still is Vital
  - Public Works and Planning
  - Taxpayers' Dividends
  - Looking Back to 1776
  - The Imperial Conference
  - Our International Cash-Book
  - Branch Factories Abroad
  - Dollar Ideas
  - America Lifts Her Face
  - Job Sharing
  - The Defense of the Dollar
  - Price Trends and Recovery
  - Looking Ahead in Foreign Trade
  - Life Insurance and Recovery
  - Industrial Housecleaning
  - Aggressive Retailing
  - Trends in the Food Trades
  - Taxpayers' Dividends
  - International Barter (Some Discussion of Toy Trade)
  - The World Economic Conference
  - Business Goodwill
- 1933
  - Looking Backward and Forward
  - The Automotive Industry "Carries On"
  - The Test-Tube Route to Recovery
  - Small-Town Chambers of Commerce
  - Electricity Opens New Doors
  - America on the High Seas
  - Lincoln and Business
  - Back to Quality
  - Government and Business